<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN"
    "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
  <!ENTITY legal SYSTEM "legal.xml">
  <!ENTITY appversion "2.6">
  <!ENTITY manrevision "2.6">
  <!ENTITY date "Feb 2004">
  <!ENTITY app "<application>GNOME Tali</application>">
  <!ENTITY appname "GNOME Tali">
  <!ENTITY version "2.6">
]>

<article id="index" lang="da">
  <articleinfo>
   <title>GNOME Tali Dokumentation</title>

    <publisher> 
      <publishername>GNOME Documentation Project </publishername>
    </publisher>
  
    &legal;
  
    <revhistory>
      <revision>
        <revnumber>&appname; Manual V&manrevision;</revnumber>
        <date>&date;</date>
        <revdescription>
          <para>Converted from the original HTML by someone who doesn't speak Danish.</para>
        </revdescription>
      </revision>
    </revhistory>
  
    <releaseinfo>This manual describes version &appversion; of &appname;.
    </releaseinfo>
    <legalnotice>
      <title>Feedback</title>
      <para>To report a bug or make a suggestion regarding this game or
      this manual, follow the directions in the <ulink
      url="ghelp:gnome-feedback" type="help">GNOME Feedback Page</ulink>.
      </para>
    </legalnotice>
  </articleinfo>


  <indexterm zone="index">
    <primary>GNOME Tali</primary>
  </indexterm>

  <sect1 id="Overview">
    <title>Oversigt</title>
    <para>
    <application>Gnome tali</application> er en slags poker med
    terninger and less money.  You roll five dice three times and try to create
    the best &quot;hand.&quot;  Your two rerolls may include any or all of your
    dice.
    </para>
  
    <para>
    <application>Gnome Tali</application> is very similar to terninge spillet Yahtzee, hvilket er et varemærke
    tilhørende Hasbro, Inc.
    </para>
  </sect1>
  
  <sect1 id="Play">
    <title>Kom igang</title>


    <para>
    When play starts, you see the results of your first throw of the dice.
    </para>

    <para>
      <orderedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Click on the dice you wish to roll again and they will turn into
	   pumpkins -- thanks Tigert :)</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>
          When you have selected all the dice you wish to reroll, press
	  the &quot;Roll!&quot; button.
          </para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem><para>When you have a hand you like or have run out of chances to
	   throw the dice, click on a row corresponding to what you think
	   is your best scoring combination.  It is very possible to have
	   a score of zero and if you click on the wrong row, you
	   will be scored accordingly. (Say for example, you get
	   yahtzee -- 5 of a kind -- and click on the large straight row,
	   you will receive a zero in your large straigt score).</para>
        </listitem>
      </orderedlist>
    </para>

    <para>
You can only use each combination once, i.e. once you've entered
something in a slot, you can't change the score later if you roll a
better hand.
    </para>
  </sect1>
 
  <sect1 id="Options">
    <title>Funktioner</title>

    <variablelist><title>Computermodstandere</title>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><guimenuitem>Pause mellem kast</guimenuitem></term>
        <listitem>
		 <para>Make the computer opponents pause between rolls of the
			  dice so you can see what they are doing.  Slows down game
			  play some.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
      <varlistentry>
        <term><guimenuitem>Antal modstandere</guimenuitem></term>
        <listitem>
		 <para>Select the number of computer opponents.  You are allowed a
			  total of six human and computer players.  If you attempt to
			  increase this number near the limit, the number of human players
			  will be decreased to maintain only six total players.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>

    <variablelist>
      <title><guimenuitem>Spillernavne</guimenuitem></title>
      <varlistentry>
        <listitem>
        <para>To change the names of the players just enter new
          names in the boxes.</para>
        </listitem>
      </varlistentry>
    </variablelist>
  
  </sect1>

  <sect1 id="Strategy">
    <title>Strategi</title>

    <para>
    Spil for at vinde!  En eller anden kan skrive en yahtzee strategidokument.
    </para>

  </sect1>

</article>

